# Joey Hardy

## Sr. Software Engineer



I am an experienced engineer with a focus on architecture, design and professional development. I enjoy improving myself, but I enjoy making my team better even more. I am interested in practical functional programming and clean design pattern usage.

### Work Experience:

#### 2015-present Team Lead/Senior Developer, Taillight, LLC, Addison, TX

- Architect and plan new features, large scale refactors and maintenance for technical debt
- Planned, coordinated and executed an effort to replace all customer's devices due to the national 3G network sunset in less than a month
- Subject matter expert for payments, orders and subscriptions, with third party integrations to Stripe and Shopify
- Spearhead efforts to learn and develop better automated testing practices as a team
- Develop devops tools, define CI/CD strategy for Bamboo build and deployment plans and create framework for templating new API and frontend Next.js projects
- O Mentor junior engineers. Lead efforts to develop skills and knowledge for entire department

#### 2012-2014 Enterprise Systems Developer, Navigation Solutions, Plano, TX

- Developed embedded systems GUI/backend using third-party UI framework and proprietary data backend for GPS devices rented in Hertz rental cars. (C++, XML, SQLite, Python)
- Created and maintained SOA web services for use by websites, mobile apps and the GPS devices over cell network. (C#, Javascript, MS SQL, HTML/CSS)
- Created Android and iPhone apps which take advantage of the web services we provided for online trip planning. (C# mono, Obj-C)

#### 2009-2011 Online Web Developer, D Magazine Partners, Inc., Dallas, TX

- Implemented interim custom CMS solution tailored to fit company needs. (C#, SQL)
- O Began developing long-term solution using Umbraco, a .NET-based MVC framework.
- Maintained and created new Wordpress-based blogs for different areas of interest, such as Dallas happenings, home design and fashion. (PHP, Javascript)
- Translated designer's creatives into markup and code (Javascript, HTML, CSS)
- The website earned the City and Regional Magazine Best Website of 2012 Award.

#### Technical Skills

Technologies Node.js, React, Nextjs, Express, Mocha, Jest, Mongo, SQL, Docker, Rancher, Javascript, C#, C++, Java

Tools Git, Github, Jira, Bitbucket, Bamboo, TFS

### Open Source Contributions

#### WistiaKit

Added hooks to iOS/TvOS library to enable consumers to cache retrieved media information.

#### foundryvtt-icon

Added new features to an open source TTRPG system for distributed play

#### Education:

2006-2010 B.S. in Computer Science, University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TX